Laurkan Rodriguez

Email: laurkanr@gmail.com

A computer scientist with 5+ years of professional experience focusing on modular system architecture and reusable implementations that easily enables scalable software solutions. Dual citizen of Ireland and Barbados, with permanent residence status in Canada.

Skills

- Python, JavaScript, C++
- HTML, JSON, NoSQL, SQL, XML
- Generics, Asynchronous Programming, Neural Networks, Cryptography
- Flask, NumPy, Django, NodeJS, ReactJS, WebAssembly, G++
- UX Design, MVC, REST, CLI Automation, Web Scraping, NLP
- Constantly learning, Creative problem solver

Employment Experience

STEREO D LLC 2020 – 2021

A visual effects company handling high quality media files for multiple major production companies **Software Developer**

- Automated querying over complex structured data to generate arbitrarily formatted media
- Communicated with non-technical users to develop automated tools to improve their efficiency
- Part of team to debug reported problems in C++ and Python desktop applications

OUILLSOFT LTD 2015 – 2019

An e-learning company that specializes in creating accessible writing tools for students.

Junior Software Developer Software Developer 2015 – 2017 2017 – 2019

- UX design & implementation within a Web Environment with a focus on accessibility
- Multiple Web App Development projects utilizing an event driven architecture in JavaScript
- Prototype a system for efficient, client-side processing over large data sets with C++

Projects

- <u>HttpSpider</u>: Snowball style web spider to crawl websites and perform some basic NLP
- Python Data Structures: Set of data structure implementations in Python that I find useful.
- ArtWorksBarbados: Website for an artist to share her work and tutoring class schedule.
- Kaan Types: Library to provide uniform validation for defensive programming in JavaScript

Education

Bachelor of Science (Hons), University of Toronto

2010 - 2015

Computer Science & Cognitive Science

In addition to software engineering concepts, such as data structures and algorithms, studied a multidisciplined approach to understanding the human brain, including topics in psychology, neuroscience, Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence